<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 15:53:45 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implement Progressive Web App in Hugo using Github Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 15:53:45 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</guid><description>We all know or heard of Progressive Web Apps. I wanted to implement it because it enables web applications workable in offline, like a native app. Also it provides content faster by caching them.
With help of github actions and gulp, we can easily add it to a static site deployed in Github pages.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Add Table of Contents Anywhere in Markdown File</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-add-toc-anywhere/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:04:41 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-add-toc-anywhere/</guid><description>Hugo provides a built-in module named {{ .TableOfContents }} to generate table of contents. It is pretty handy because it generates the table of content without help of any JavaScript or CSS code. But there is a problem with it, you need to put it inside templates. You can&amp;rsquo;t render it inside the contents of the markdown file.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Use Environment Variable in Markdown Files</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-use-env-variable-in-md/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-use-env-variable-in-md/</guid><description>Hugo is a fantastic framework to generate static site from markdown and serve them. Using environment variables in templates is a breeze but using them in markdown files can be a bit tricky. You need to use custom shortcodes as workaround to resolve this issue.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; What is shortcodes Custom shortcodes Use environment variable in shortcodes By getenv variable By site variable In conclusion</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Deploy Static Site using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:59:54 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</guid><description>If you are using Hugo to generate static pages, you are familiar with CLI commands which are to build the static pages in your local machine and make push to your &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io repository. When it comes to using Hugo for blogging, compared to platforms like Medium or WordPress, it is very painful because you do not have any web interface to make changes whenever you want or wherever you want.</description></item><item><title>Implement Newsletter Subscription Using Staticman</title><link>https://ruddra.com/implement-newsletters-using-staticman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:12:08 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/implement-newsletters-using-staticman/</guid><description>In this article, I am going to share how you can set up a newsletter subscription using Staticman. No need to use third party newsletter subscription services.
Collecting data in static sites or serverless sites(with POST request) is a hassle because you don&amp;rsquo;t have a server to receive POST requests and store data.</description></item><item><title>Bye Bye Ghost, Hello Hugo</title><link>https://ruddra.com/moving-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/moving-to-hugo/</guid><description>“The Only Thing That Is Constant Is Change -” ― Heraclitus
This blog site has changed quite a lot since the begining. I initially developed it as a Django application. It was part of my learning process, and I hosted it in a private shared server.
But unfortunatly, good days came to an end, I had to give up that hosting for costing.</description></item></channel></rss>