<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on Ruddra</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on Ruddra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:53:28 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ship Application with Database Inside Docker Container</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-ship-database-with-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:53:28 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-ship-database-with-container/</guid><description>DISCLAIMER: This is not the recommended process. Ideally you should have the database running in a separate container and use network to interact with that container.
Usually, we don’t ship application with the database inside the same container. But sometimes we are forced to do that. In this article we are going to see a minimalist way of shipping application with database built-in inside docker container.</description></item><item><title>Tips on Using Volume, Entrypoint and Ignore Files in Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-volume-entrypoint-ignorefile/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:56:04 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-volume-entrypoint-ignorefile/</guid><description>Have you worked with Docker before? Do you think you have trouble with it, like when you are developing an application, you need to build every time to see the results, or thinking of the best way to load data in DB, or may be you are annoyed because there are lots of markdown files, screenshots etc that are taking a lot of space in your container.</description></item><item><title>Tips on Using Docker Compose, Build Argument and Environment Variable</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-compose-arg-env/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-compose-arg-env/</guid><description>Imagine, you have some microservices and you want to use API from one service to another, how can you do that if all of them are running in different docker container? Docker Compose has a solution for you.
Suppose you want to deploy a project in test, stage and production environment with same Dockerfile for all of them through a single Dockerfile.</description></item><item><title>Tips on Writing Dockerfile, Reduce Sizes and Build Time of Docker Image</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-write-dockerfile-and-reduce-size-build-time-for-image/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:15:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/docker-write-dockerfile-and-reduce-size-build-time-for-image/</guid><description>For the past couple of years, I have been creating Dockerfile for different projects. based on those experiences I am going to share some tips on writing docker files to communication between containers.
*FYI: before reading this article, please read the article from official docker blog site to learn about best practices for creating Dockerfile.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro KDE Virtual Desktop Management and Visual Improvement Shortcuts</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/manjaro-kde-plasma-workspace-visual-improvements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 02:40:51 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/manjaro-kde-plasma-workspace-visual-improvements/</guid><description>For the past couple of days, I am testing out Manjaro linux. Most of the time, I was working with KDE Plasma Edition. In my opinion, it is the most beautiful desktop environment from Manjaro official distributions.
I am a fan of Ubuntu Unity workspaces and wanted to use similar features in KDE plasma as well.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro Tips and Tricks</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/manjaro-tricks-and-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 01:32:28 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/manjaro-tricks-and-tips/</guid><description>Recently I tried out Manjaro operating system, and did some experiment with XFCE and KDE desktop environments. Here I am going to share some tips and tricks to setup Manjaro in you machine.
This article is part of a series based on Manjaro. Tips shared here are applicable for all Manjaro desktop distributions.</description></item><item><title>Bye Bye Ghost, Hello Hugo</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/moving-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/moving-to-hugo/</guid><description>“The Only Thing That Is Constant Is Change -” ― Heraclitus
This blog site has changed quite a lot since the begining. I initially developed it as a Django application. It was part of my learning process, and I hosted it in a private shared server.
But unfortunatly, good days came to an end, I had to give up that hosting for costing.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Hacks: Launching Chrome Apps at Startup</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/ubuntu-protip-launching-chrome-apps-at-startup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/ubuntu-protip-launching-chrome-apps-at-startup/</guid><description>Chrome apps are really handy when you don&amp;rsquo;t want to overhaul your system with apps for every little purpose. Starting those apps at startup can be used instead of manually starting them every time you want to use them. Like starting the messenger at startup of the system. To do that.</description></item></channel></rss>