<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</title><link>https://ruddra.com/</link><description>Recent content on Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 08:22:02 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convert TFRecords to Pandas and Pandas to TFRecords</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tfrecords-pandas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 08:22:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/tfrecords-pandas/</guid><description>The TFRecord (Tensor Flow Records) format is a simple format for storing a sequence of binary records. It is much more efficient storage because it can take up less space than the original data. Aside from that, you can partition TFRecords into multiple files. In this article, we are going to see how you can convert Pandas Dataframe (essentially from a CSV) to TFRecords or vice versa.</description></item><item><title>Useful Tips to Help You with Starting Your First Professional Project</title><link>https://ruddra.com/things-you-should-know-before-starting-a-professional-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 17:31:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/things-you-should-know-before-starting-a-professional-project/</guid><description>If you have a CS background, then you are bound to have encounters with professional projects. Before starting one, you should keep a few things in mind; otherwise, working could be a bit difficult. Here are some tips for a jump start in your professional project development. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Knowing your stakeholders All IDEs are good IDEs Git is your friend Keeping only one copy of the project Knowing your project environment Checking the test cases Being aware of the culture Not being afraid In conclusion Knowing your stakeholders Before starting the project, it is a good idea to talk with the stakeholders of this project.</description></item><item><title>Use NVIDIA Cuda in Docker for Data Science Projects</title><link>https://ruddra.com/use-cuda-in-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:39:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/use-cuda-in-docker/</guid><description>When I was working with data science project running in Docker, I found that working with huge data can be problematic. Even tools like PyArrow is not fast enough in Docker. But when I debugged the logs, I saw that if I could give it access to NVIDIA Cuda, then it would be much faster.</description></item><item><title>Add Search Functionality in Hugo</title><link>https://ruddra.com/add-search-functionality-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/add-search-functionality-hugo/</guid><description>Adding search functionality make your website more accessible and usable to the stakeholders. In this article, I am going to share on how you can add this in a static site generated by hugo. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Expose JSON output Create layout Build the search page Add lunr.js file Add search functionality Add HTML Add JavaScript In conclusion Expose JSON output In the first step, we need to expose the json output for the files.</description></item><item><title>Rollout your Google fonts faster with Cloudflare Cache</title><link>https://ruddra.com/cloudflare-cache-google-fonts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:00:57 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/cloudflare-cache-google-fonts/</guid><description>If you are already using Cloudflare, you know that Cloudflare caches fonts (and other contents). But it won’t work if you are using Google font’s CDN. Cloudflare has a detailed guide on how to improve Google fonts performance, but it heavily relies on workers, which might cost a lot of money if your website has a lot of users.</description></item><item><title>Create Workflow using Alacritty, Fish Shell, tmux, and Vim</title><link>https://ruddra.com/alacritty-fish-tmux-vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 22:22:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/alacritty-fish-tmux-vim/</guid><description>Even if you use Vim, it does not mean that you have to code in a plain, stuttering, and boring terminal. In this article, we are going to see how to set up a beautiful interface for coding, which is highly configurable yet highly automated. Without further aduo, let&amp;rsquo;s go!! Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Alacritty Fish Shell tmux Vim Save configuration In conclusion Alacritty Alacritty is a GPU accelerated terminal powered by OpenGL.</description></item><item><title>Journey to Vim</title><link>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 22:07:44 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-vim/</guid><description>If you are comfortable with your current IDE but still want to try something interesting which might increase your ✌️ productivity ✌️, then you can look into Vim. This article is not setting up your Vim, you will find thousands of articles on Google. Rather, I want to share my thoughts which might motivate(or demotivate) you to use Vim.</description></item><item><title>Run Github Actions Within Monthly Limit</title><link>https://ruddra.com/run-github-actions-within-limits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 18:51:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/run-github-actions-within-limits/</guid><description>Suppose you are using Github free plan, you are running actions in your private repo and keep exceeding the monthly minutes limit, then this article is going to help you to make optimized usage of the actions minutes in step by step manner. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: run workflow on schedule instead of push Step two: run workflow manually only if you push In conclusion Step one: run workflow on schedule instead of push Rather than running the workflow on every push, you can run it in a periodic manner.</description></item><item><title>Serverless and Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/serverless-and-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 22:47:51 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/serverless-and-actions/</guid><description>In JAMStack(aka static sites), we use different paid/free services for things like using Disqus for commenting, MailChimp for newsletters etc. These services come with a tradeoff, for example lack of privacy, bloated JavaScript and many more.
What if we can build them on our own using a serverless stack, with low to no cost and almost zero maintenance?</description></item><item><title>Fix Python After Brew Upgrade in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/fix-python-after-brew-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:25:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/fix-python-after-brew-upgrade/</guid><description>When you run brew upgrade or brew upgrade &amp;lt;package&amp;gt;, all the packages are upgraded or packages linked to that particular package you want to upgrade gets updated. For Python, if the version upgrade is minor, then it should be fine. But major updates break a lot of development setup like, if you are used to develop using virtual environment, then you might have re-install every package.</description></item><item><title>Beginner's Guide on Web Scraping using Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/beginners-guide-on-scraping-using-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:21:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/beginners-guide-on-scraping-using-python/</guid><description>When it comes to web scraping, you have to keep in mind that it is not the coding skill rather cunning observations will get you results. Sometimes the data you get comes in a straight forward way, other times the website does not want you to crawl itself. Either way you will get the data, but it takes time depending on how many puzzles do you have to solve before getting it.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Get Perfect Score in Google PageSpeed</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-get-perfect-pagespeed-score/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 15:53:45 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-get-perfect-pagespeed-score/</guid><description>You will see many Hugo themes boast perfect scores on Google PageSpeed Insights(PSI). To be honest, most of them are not as pretty as others and lack a significant amount of JavaScript(or no JavaScript at all). But, it does not matter anymore. Because you can use any theme(or develop on your own) and get an almost perfect score in PSI if you implement the following steps.</description></item><item><title>Progressive Web App in Hugo using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 15:53:45 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</guid><description>We all know or heard of Progressive Web Apps. I wanted to implement it because it enables web applications workable in offline, like a native app. Also it provides content faster by caching them.
With help of github actions and gulp, we can easily add it to a static site deployed in Github pages.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Add Table of Contents Anywhere in Markdown File</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-add-toc-anywhere/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:04:41 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-add-toc-anywhere/</guid><description>Hugo provides a built-in module named {{ .TableOfContents }} to generate table of contents. It is pretty handy because it generates the table of content without help of any JavaScript or CSS code. But there is a problem with it, you need to put it inside templates. You can&amp;rsquo;t render it inside the contents of the markdown file.</description></item><item><title>Reduce Build Time for Images with Data Science Packages</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-reduce-build-time-for-data-science-packages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:36:27 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-reduce-build-time-for-data-science-packages/</guid><description>If you want to use data science packages like numpy, scipy, pandas etc with your docker container and using pip to install them, then it will take forever to build the images. Because pip compiles the C extended code and that compilation needs a lot of time. For numpy it took me around 4 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Create a Web App with JWT Authentication using Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-jwt-auth-app-in-10-mins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-jwt-auth-app-in-10-mins/</guid><description>Let us say, you need an authentication service in a rush, which needs to be cutting edge and uses JWT based authentication. Or you need a stand alone authentication service to be plugged in with other microservices. Do not worry, you can create one in 10 minutes. All you need to have is Python and Docker installed in your machine.</description></item><item><title>Trigger AWS CodeBuild When a Git Tag is Pushed</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-git-tags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 20:19:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-git-tags/</guid><description>AWS CodeBuild has nice integration with different Git repository hosting service providers(like GitHub, BitBucket, even amazon&amp;rsquo;s own CodeCommit etc). Even using WebHook is pretty easy. You can start a build in CodeBuild for every push, pull, PR created, PR merged etc. But it can be bit tricky when it comes to trigger for every tag push only, as it us not a default event type provided by CodeBuild.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Use Environment Variable in Markdown Files</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-use-env-variable-in-md/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-use-env-variable-in-md/</guid><description>Hugo is a fantastic framework to generate static site from markdown and serve them. Using environment variables in templates is a breeze but using them in markdown files can be a bit tricky. You need to use custom shortcodes as workaround to resolve this issue. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; What is shortcodes Custom shortcodes Use environment variable in shortcodes By getenv variable By site variable In conclusion What is shortcodes Now the question comes, what is shorcode?</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Results</title><link>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:02 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones-results/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we are going visualize the data, discuss about the results and draw a conclusion.</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Methodology</title><link>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones-methodology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones-methodology/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this article we are going to describe the methodology we used in step by step: Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: New York city data with latitude and longitude Step two: New York city data with population Step three: combine step one and step two Step four: collect hospital data from Foursquare Step five: collect hospital bed data from NYS Health Profile Step six: combine step four and step five Step seven: combine data from step three and step six Step eight: add bed and icu per hundred people to data frame Step nine: K-means clustering Step ten: merge cluster labels with dataset Step eleven: see which borough goes to which cluster Step twelve: neighborhoods without hospital Conclusion Step one: New York city data with latitude and longitude We are using requests to get the json data from nyc dataset and stored it in a data frame.</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Data Preparation</title><link>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/project-battle-of-capstones/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this report has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we will discuss about business problem and data preparation steps. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Business problem Data Approach Data preparation Source code Conclusion Business problem Right now, New York is one of the worst hit state by COVID-19 in USA.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Deploy Static Site using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:59:54 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</guid><description>If you are using Hugo to generate static pages, you are familiar with CLI commands which are to build the static pages in your local machine and make push to your &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io repository. When it comes to using Hugo for blogging, compared to platforms like Medium or WordPress, it is very painful because you do not have any web interface to make changes whenever you want or wherever you want.</description></item><item><title>Ship Application with Database Inside Docker Container</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-ship-database-with-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:53:28 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-ship-database-with-container/</guid><description>DISCLAIMER: This is not the recommended process. Ideally you should have the database running in a separate container and use network to interact with that container.
Usually, we don’t ship application with the database inside the same container. But sometimes we are forced to do that. In this article we are going to see a minimalist way of shipping application with database built-in inside docker container.</description></item><item><title>Maintain Authentication Layer from Redux Middleware Using React Router</title><link>https://ruddra.com/reactjs-maintain-auth-layer-from-redux-middleware-router/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/reactjs-maintain-auth-layer-from-redux-middleware-router/</guid><description>Maintaining authentication layer in ReactJS can be painful. Back in the old days(even now-a-days), you needed to override every componentDidMount method in class based components to see if the user is authenticated. In the latest ReactJS, there are hooks(specially useEffect) where you need to write these checks. Either way, some codes will be redundant.</description></item><item><title>Use Docker for Accessing Database in AWS CodeBuild</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:08:29 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-database/</guid><description>AWS CodeBuild is an extraordinary tool for building your code. Recently I have been using it to build projects and store docker images in AWS ECR. During those CodeBuild processes, I needed Database for running tests. As the need of the Database was for a limited time and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay extra for it(that is why I did not use AWS RDS), I decided to create database using docker inside CodeBuild.</description></item><item><title>Basic Networking in Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/networking-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:50:56 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/networking-with-docker/</guid><description>We already know that Docker is used for containerization. But networking in docker makes it even better tool for deployment. You can make standalone deployments in containers and communicate between them, or make containers act as host, or even assign mac addresses to containers and act them as devices. It does not matter which host machine you are in, you can make dockers communicate in-between them.</description></item><item><title>Implement Newsletter Subscription Using Staticman</title><link>https://ruddra.com/implement-newsletters-using-staticman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:12:08 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/implement-newsletters-using-staticman/</guid><description>Collecting data in static sites or serverless sites(with POST request) is a hassle because you don&amp;rsquo;t have a server to receive POST requests and store data. But Staticman is here to help. It will enable users to make POST requests, that will allow you to gather these data. In this article, I am going to tweak Staticman a little to implement newsletter subscription.</description></item><item><title>How to Use Volume, EntryPoint and Ignore Files in Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-volume-entrypoint-ignorefile/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:56:04 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-volume-entrypoint-ignorefile/</guid><description>Have you worked with Docker before? Do you think you have trouble with it, like when you are developing an application, you need to build every time to see the results, or thinking of the best way to load data in DB, or may be you are annoyed because there are lots of markdown files, screenshots etc that are taking a lot of space in your container.</description></item><item><title>Why Use Docker Compose, Build Argument and Environment Variable</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-compose-arg-env/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-compose-arg-env/</guid><description>Imagine, you have some microservices and you want to use API from one service to another, how can you do that if all of them are running in different docker container? Docker Compose has a solution for you.
Suppose you want to deploy a project in test, stage and production environment with same Dockerfile for all of them through a single Dockerfile.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Dockerfile to Reduce Size and Build Time of Docker Images</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-write-dockerfile-and-reduce-size-build-time-for-image/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:15:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-write-dockerfile-and-reduce-size-build-time-for-image/</guid><description>For the past couple of years, I have been creating Dockerfile for different projects. based on those experiences I am going to share some tips on writing docker files to communication between containers.
_FYI: before reading this article, please read the article from official docker blog site to learn about best practices for creating Dockerfile.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro KDE Virtual Desktop Management and Visual Improvement Tips</title><link>https://ruddra.com/manjaro-kde-plasma-workspace-visual-improvements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 02:40:51 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/manjaro-kde-plasma-workspace-visual-improvements/</guid><description>For the past couple of days, I am testing out Manjaro linux. Most of the time, I was working with KDE Plasma Edition. In my opinion, it is the most beautiful desktop environment from Manjaro official distributions.
I am a fan of Ubuntu Unity workspaces and wanted to use similar features in KDE plasma as well.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro: Tricks and Tips</title><link>https://ruddra.com/manjaro-tricks-and-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 01:32:28 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/manjaro-tricks-and-tips/</guid><description>Recently I tried out Manjaro operating system, and did some experiment with XFCE and KDE desktop environments. Here I am going to share some tips and tricks to setup Manjaro in you machine. Now, let us dive in. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Copy bash history to ZSH Backlight On using terminal Install visual studio code(VS Code) Wireless headphone muddy sound fix GPG verify key error fix Package managers AUR or build your own packages Pacman Snap Bootstrap manjaro setup IOS/Android file copy Rows and columns in workspaces Backup and restore Copy environment to other machine Copy bash history to ZSH Lets say you are using bash for a long time, and now you have installed ZSH.</description></item><item><title>Django Access URL Arguments Through Middleware</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-store-url-argument-through-middleware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 22:06:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-store-url-argument-through-middleware/</guid><description>Lets say you have an API which is being used by many stores. Now for a specific store ABC, they want to have a different response format. So how would you make this implementation generic without making different views for store ABC? Simple, use middleware. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; How it works Usage Another usage scenario How it works First update the url like this:</description></item><item><title>Build and Configure Plugins Inside Solr Using Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/solr-docker-plugin-install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:16:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/solr-docker-plugin-install/</guid><description>Adding a plugin to Solr is relatively simple process. In this article, we are going to see how to add a plugin by creating a jar file using a docker container, then add that to a Solr which also runs inside docker container. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Building the plugin Workflow for building the plugin Example of solr image Explanation Run solr Without docker-compose With docker-compose Configure plugin inside docker In conclusion Building the plugin Workflow for building the plugin Steps for building a Solr plugin inside Solr docker file are like this:</description></item><item><title>Use VS Code Inside Docker Container for Development</title><link>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-remote-docker-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 18:54:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-remote-docker-development/</guid><description>VS Code is the most popular IDE at the moment. You can use it for developing applications in almost any programming language. In addition to that, you can do remote development in Docker,VM etc. In this post, we are going to discuss about how to use Docker Environment in VS Code.</description></item><item><title>Django Serialize ForeignKey, ManyToMany, Instance, Property Method</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-serialize-foreignkey-m2m-property-instance-fields/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 23:12:26 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-serialize-foreignkey-m2m-property-instance-fields/</guid><description>Django’s serialization framework provides a mechanism for “translating” Django models into other formats. Usually they are in json output, yaml output, XML output, GeoJSON output etc text based formats.
Here, we are going to supercharge these serializers to do more things, even try to render properties method and instance method.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Django App in Sub Directory Using OpenShift</title><link>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-subpath-openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 20:36:44 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-subpath-openshift/</guid><description>When you are using OpenShift, you will be using routes to expose a route from a service. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to expose a path in example.com/dummy. When you do that for a django application(without any reverse proxy server), it usually becomes a problem, because the sub directory does not work well with Django&amp;rsquo;s urls.</description></item><item><title>Install MySQL and MySQLClient (Python) in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/install-mysqlclient-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 23:59:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/install-mysqlclient-macos/</guid><description>Connecting to MySQL from Python in MacOS is a very problematic and painful process. In this post, we are going to see how to install MySQL and connect a Python application to it using mysqlclient. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: install Homebrew Step two: install MySQL Step three: install MySQL-Connector-C Step four: install XCode-Select Step five: install OpenSSL Step six: unlink MySQL and link MySQL-Connector-C Step seven: install mysqlclient Step eight: link MySQL back again Step nine: add mysqlclient in virtual env(optional) In conclusion Step one: install Homebrew You need to install Homebrew in you local machine.</description></item><item><title>Create Proxy Object in Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/python-proxy-object/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 01:06:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/python-proxy-object/</guid><description>Lets say you have been using a class named ClassA, objects created from that class has been used in many places. Now you have a requirement that you need to make a simillar class ClassB, which has almost simillar functionality. Objects of ClassA and ClassB will have simillar method signatures, and could be swapable.</description></item><item><title>Do More in S3 Using Django Storage and Boto3</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-boto3-useful-functions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 01:49:10 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-boto3-useful-functions/</guid><description>Today, I am going to write about few useful snippets/functionalities which I have used for Amazon S3 or any S3 compatible storage using Boto3 and Django Storage. FYI, this post focuses on using S3 with Django.
So without further ado, let us begin. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Configuring S3 Using S3 which it does not belong to AWS Serve S3 in different domain(through cloudFront or varnish) Create new bucket See all buckets Change access control to a bucket Delete objects from a bucket(also bucket itself) Use different folders when storing media and static contents Make &amp;lsquo;collect static&amp;rsquo; faster Check ACL status In conclusion Configuring S3 When using django storage, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to put configurations like ~/.</description></item><item><title>Django: Save Unknown Object in Database</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-save-unknown-object-in-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:38:04 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-save-unknown-object-in-database/</guid><description>Suppose you are dealing with a poorly written API, which returns different type of objects at different scenarios. For example, sometimes it returns a string(ie. abcd), sometimes it returns a list(ie. [1,2,3,4]), or maybe None. Now, you are suppose to save that data, which you can&amp;rsquo;t predict. As you can&amp;rsquo;t predict the data type of object, you can&amp;rsquo;t design your Django Model accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Django: Ordering by Linked List for Model Objects</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-model-linked-list/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 14:58:58 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-model-linked-list/</guid><description>Linked list is a data structure where each object has points to next. In django, linked list can provide an interesting solution when it comes to custom ordering/grouping issues.
Lets think of an example like this= you are making a blog site, and you have made a Post Model like this:</description></item><item><title>Django: Changing User Model in Mid-Project</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-custom-user-migration-mid-phase-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-custom-user-migration-mid-phase-project/</guid><description>Every now and then I see some questions pop up in Stack Overflow with title:
ValueError: Related model &amp;lsquo;app.User&amp;rsquo; cannot be resolved
This is a very common issue and pops up when the user tries to run the migration. So, lets talk more about what is this problem and how can we solve it.</description></item><item><title>Testing for Django Rest Framework with Factory Boy and Faker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tdd-drf-factory-boy-faker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/tdd-drf-factory-boy-faker/</guid><description>“I&amp;rsquo;m not a great programmer; I&amp;rsquo;m just a good programmer with great habits.” ― Kent Beck
Test Driven Development - in short TDD is a practice where you write the tests first then the actual code. It makes the code less vulnerable and it makes a testable software rather than writing the software, then test it.</description></item><item><title>Bye Bye Ghost, Hello Hugo</title><link>https://ruddra.com/moving-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/moving-to-hugo/</guid><description>“The Only Thing That Is Constant Is Change -” ― Heraclitus
This blog site has changed quite a lot since the begining. I initially developed it as a Django application. It was part of my learning process, and I hosted it in a private shared server.
But unfortunatly, good days came to an end, I had to give up that hosting for costing.</description></item><item><title>Control Application Flow from Redux Middleware using React Router 4</title><link>https://ruddra.com/control-application-flow-from-redux-middleware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 17:25:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/control-application-flow-from-redux-middleware/</guid><description>While developing application in ReactJs with Redux and React Router 4, what I felt is that, there is no direct relationship between application&amp;rsquo;s state and routing. We needed to create those connections inside Components. In each component, we needed to check application state and based on that we made decisions where to go next(if needed).</description></item><item><title>Migration From Ghost 1.25.2 to 2.2</title><link>https://ruddra.com/migration-from-ghost-1-2-to-2-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/migration-from-ghost-1-2-to-2-2/</guid><description>This post is no longer valid as I have moved to Hugo 😄
Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Verdict Verdict I have just migrated the site from Ghost 1.25.2 to 2.2. As every growth comes with some inevitable pain, thus you can expect a lot of things are broken.
Here all the URLS have been updated.</description></item><item><title>Automated Deployment to OpenShift Using Jenkins and Webhook</title><link>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-pipeline-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-pipeline-deployment/</guid><description>The last post was about defining the pipelines. Now it is time to execute them. Also, at the end, we are going to show how to integrate webhook in your repository, so that for a specific event(like Push, Pull request merge etc) it will trigger the pipelines to automatically deploy the latest code to servers.</description></item><item><title>Writing Jenkins Pipeline For OpenShift Deployment: Part Two</title><link>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-jenkins-pipeline-two/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 20:41:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-jenkins-pipeline-two/</guid><description>In previous article, we covered step 1-5 which would prepare the code and make sure it is ready to be deployed to OpenShift. Now we are going to use the next steps to deploy that code. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step 6: create build configuration in OpenShift Step 7: build image Step 8: deploy to OpenShift in DEV Step 9: promote image to STAGE Step 10: deploy to OpenShift in STAGE Step 11: scale in STAGE Conclusion Step 6: create build configuration in OpenShift After Step 5, we will have a nice compressed file containing what we need for building our app in openshift.</description></item><item><title>Writing Jenkins Pipeline For OpenShift Deployment: Part One</title><link>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-jenkins-pipeline-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:41:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-jenkins-pipeline-one/</guid><description>Pipeline is a set of instructions, which will be executed as per given sequence and produce a output. Jenkins Pipeline is simply writing these instructions in Jenkins. These pipelines can be written in Groovy.
In previous post we have defined deployment structure and made necessary preparations for deployment of a python+gunicorn+nginx+jenkins based project.</description></item><item><title>Deploy A Python App to OpenShift: Planning and Preparations</title><link>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-pipeline-preparation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 15:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/openshift-python-pipeline-preparation/</guid><description>Deploying a Python application to OpenShift is fairly easy. Write a Dockerfile and run oc new-app /path/to/Dockerfile, that&amp;rsquo;s it!! But if you want implement a full fledged modern CI/CD using Jenkins and openshift, you need to do little more than that. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into it.
We will explain about the whole process in three articles:</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://ruddra.com/privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/privacy/</guid><description>It is ruddra.com&amp;rsquo;s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website. This Privacy Policy applies to https://ruddra.com (hereinafter, &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;https://ruddra.com&amp;rdquo;). Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Effective date Cookie Policy Email Policy User Information Policy Third Party Privacy Policy External Usage Children Policy Log Policy Contact Us Effective date Effective date of this privacy policy is August 11, 2018.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Django to OpenShift Using Jenkins Pipeline(CI/CD)</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-openshift-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 17:51:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-openshift-pipeline/</guid><description>Using Jenkins pipeline, you can easily automate your deployments in OpenShift. In this post, we are going to use this powerful tool to deploy a Django project. But before we start, one thing I need to mention is that, this project has been tested on in Minishift 1.2.0, OpenShift v3.9.0 and Kubernetes v1.</description></item><item><title>Boilerplate For Angular 1.X and Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/boilerplate-django-with-angularjs-powered-by-webpack2-yarn-docker-drf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/boilerplate-django-with-angularjs-powered-by-webpack2-yarn-docker-drf/</guid><description>This post is deprecated. Use it at your own risk
Simple and clean boilerplate for using django and angular 1.x together, with basic structure comes built-in. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Tech Stack Prerequisite Setup frontend Setup docker Setup backend Usage Local settings sample Screenshots Tech Stack Python3 Django 1.11.6, Django Rest Framework Webpack 2 JavaScript(ES6)/AngularJS 1.</description></item><item><title>Migration from Ghost 0.11 to 1.XX Using Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/migrating-from-ghost-11-to-1-xx-using-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 07:37:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/migrating-from-ghost-11-to-1-xx-using-docker/</guid><description>Ghost had formulated lots changes when they released version 1.XX. So, when you try to upgrade from 0.11 to 1.XX, you can follow the following steps. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps Export backup Rename old content Copy to a seperate directory Create cocker compose file Start docker containers Setup ghost admin Import file Change Theme Regarding updating handlebar files In conclusion Steps FYI, you can also use the following steps if you want run Ghost in Docker and import your existing settings.</description></item><item><title>[Travel] Bandarban: In Search of Waterfalls</title><link>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-nafakhum-amiakhum-satbhaikhum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:18:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-nafakhum-amiakhum-satbhaikhum/</guid><description>Bandarban is a heaven for trekking for Bangladeshi people. There are lots of hills around the district, and there are some amazing waterfall as well. I visited three amazing waterfalls named Nafakhum, AmiaKhum, Satbhaikhum. Khum means waterfall in Marma language. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Thanchi Remakri Nafakhum Amiakhum Padma Jhiri Tindu Thanchi captured on the way to Thanchi</description></item><item><title>[Travel] Bandarban: Journey to Keokradong</title><link>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-journey-to-keokaradong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 16:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-journey-to-keokaradong/</guid><description>Bandarban is a beautiful district of Bangladesh. You will see lots of amazing mountains which are part of Arakan range. Keokradong is the 3rd highest pick**(after Tajingdong and Saka Haphong, references are here) of Bangladesh, which is situated in Bandarbans. So today I am going to share my experience visiting there.</description></item><item><title>[Travel] Journey to the Land of Thunder Dragon</title><link>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-bhutan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 18:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-bhutan/</guid><description>I went to Bhutan on September, 2015. It was my best trip ever, really ever. From Dhaka, we went there by DRUK AIR. We(me and two of my friends) landed in Paro Airport. It was really wonderful airport, it was small but clean and organised. After getting out of the plan, a chilling air struck us, and instantly we knew, we gonna like this country.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Django to OpenShift 3 Powered by MySQL and Gunicorn</title><link>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-to-openshift-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 13:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-to-openshift-3/</guid><description>If you want to use OpenShift for deploying Django, you can follow this post and simply do that. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn Kubernetes. We will use docker file only. No other fancy stuff.
Also, before starting, I am also hoping you are little bit familiar with OpenShift 3 and oc tools.</description></item><item><title>Use VS Code for Python and Django Development</title><link>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-for-python-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 16:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-for-python-development/</guid><description>Visual Studio Code is an editor developed by Microsoft. I have been using this editor for Python development for sometime now. Previously I have been using PyCharm Community Edition for development, but I had to switch to an editor which was less resource consuming than PyCharm, since I have been using VS Code.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Hacks: Launching Chrome Apps at Startup</title><link>https://ruddra.com/ubuntu-protip-launching-chrome-apps-at-startup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:12:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/ubuntu-protip-launching-chrome-apps-at-startup/</guid><description>Chrome apps are really handy when you don&amp;rsquo;t want to overhaul your system with apps for every little purpose. Starting those apps at startup can be used instead of manually starting them every time you want to use them. Like starting the messenger at startup of the system. To do that.</description></item><item><title>Play With Pillow</title><link>https://ruddra.com/play-with-pillow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 14:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/play-with-pillow/</guid><description>Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t heard PIL? It&amp;rsquo;s an image processing library made by python (Python Image Library). Pillow is an extension of it. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Installation Resize image Crop image in box shape Resize image and crop in center to convert it to a fixed size Paste image over a background image Draw text over an image Adjast brightness of an image Adjast color of an image Save the PIL image in django models or serve as django file Convert to webp Convert to JPG/JPEG And Many more Installation So installing pillow is really easy:</description></item><item><title>Python: Selenium with PhantomJs to capture Screenshots</title><link>https://ruddra.com/python-selenium-with-phantomjs-to-capture-screenshots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/python-selenium-with-phantomjs-to-capture-screenshots/</guid><description>This article is deprecated as PhantomJs has been deprecated from Selenium as driver.
PhantomJS is a headless WebKit script-able with a JavaScript API. It has fast and native support for various web standards: DOM handling, CSS selector, JSON, Canvas, and SVG. And Selenium is a portable software-testing framework for web applications.</description></item><item><title>Documentation Of Django Encrypt File</title><link>https://ruddra.com/documentation-of-django-encrypt-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 18:52:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/documentation-of-django-encrypt-file/</guid><description>This is no longer maintained. Use it at your own risk.
Django Encrypt File is a simple Library which can be used to encrypt uploaded files and store them. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Installation Basic usage Using in the view Advance example(with models) Model defination Encrypt view Decrypt view Notes Installation Use pip to install it:</description></item><item><title>Docker: Use Celery in Django(Redis as Broker)</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-do-stuff-using-celery-using-redis-as-broker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 15:43:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-do-stuff-using-celery-using-redis-as-broker/</guid><description>In previous two posts, we have deployed Django with Postgres, Nginx, now its time to do some async stuff using Celery. In this post, I will do the magic tricks first, explain them later. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Add &amp;lsquo;Celery&amp;rsquo; to django Make a simple async task Explanations Need proof that this works Add &amp;lsquo;Celery&amp;rsquo; to django To add celery, we need make a container for celery.</description></item><item><title>Serve Static Files by Nginx from Django using Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/serve-static-files-by-nginx-from-django-using-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 17:24:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/serve-static-files-by-nginx-from-django-using-docker/</guid><description>This is more of a follow up post of my previous article.
Before I start, I am assuming you have successfully deployed django using docker and nginx, but having some problems serving static files. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps Update Steps No worries, it is easy. Just follow these steps:
1. In your django settings.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Django, Gunicorn, NGINX, Postgresql using Docker</title><link>https://ruddra.com/docker-django-nginx-postgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 13:47:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/docker-django-nginx-postgres/</guid><description>This post is based on this article on docker documentation.
I will be extending this post by serving django+gunicorn using Nginx, also I will using Postgresql docker container to use it as database. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps Create django project Add &amp;lsquo;requirement.pip&amp;rsquo; Create &amp;lsquo;Dockerfile&amp;rsquo; Install &amp;lsquo;docker-compose&amp;rsquo; Add configuration to &amp;lsquo;docker-compose.</description></item><item><title>Make MacOS Notifications From RSS Feed Using Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</guid><description>Today we are going to see how make OSX notifications from RSS Feed of any website using Python.
So first of all, let us see how to make a simple notification. We are going to use AppleScript for this. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Command for notification in AppleScript Start coding for application Integrate AppleScript in application In conclusion Command for notification in AppleScript Go to terminal and Type:</description></item><item><title>Make .CSV file using MySQL and Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</guid><description>In this blog, I am going to show how to develop an application by which we can make .csv files from MySQL database using Python. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps SQL command Run SQL command in python To csv In conclusion Steps SQL command Now, let us start by getting data from Database.</description></item><item><title>Django 1.7 and Scrapy</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-1-7-scrapy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 15:45:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-1-7-scrapy/</guid><description>This post is deprecated. Use it at your own risk.
Today I am going to share how to use Scrapy and Django together to crawl to a website and store scraped data to Database using Django. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Project Setup: Django Project Setup: Scrapy Screenshots Project Setup: Django First, let us build a Django application using the following commands.</description></item><item><title>Make a Blog using Django Part 2</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:29:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-2/</guid><description>This post is now deprecated. Please follow the official tutorial for creating your first django application.
From previous post, you have configured and ran django, also added admin site to the django.
To view the working source of this tutorial, check here at: https://github.com/ruddra/myblog/
Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Create entry in database Templates Separating views Create entry in database Now click on the myblog section and click add to add new blog.</description></item><item><title>Make a Blog using Django Part 1</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:29:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-1/</guid><description>This post is now deprecated. Please follow the official tutorial for creating your first django application.
&amp;ldquo;Making a blog using django&amp;rdquo; - is probably the most made tutorial of Django. This post is no different. But I made this in my own way using some of django&amp;rsquo;s built-in features so that less coding is required and making it more understandable with minimum packages to use.</description></item><item><title>Change Column Headers in Django Tables 2</title><link>https://ruddra.com/change-column-headers-django-tables2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/change-column-headers-django-tables2/</guid><description>Django Tables2 is a package which displays table directly from queryset. It shows column header based on object&amp;rsquo;s attribute name. But if someone wants to override it, how can he/she do that? Here is a easy solution. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Model class Table class View class Model class Suppose we have a model class like this:</description></item><item><title>Dynamically construct filters based on string input using SQLAlchemy</title><link>https://ruddra.com/dynamically-constructing-filters-based-on-string-input-using-sqlalchemy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/dynamically-constructing-filters-based-on-string-input-using-sqlalchemy/</guid><description>Here I am going to write a dynamic filter. This filter is made for python 3. It will take query or model class and filter condition as input, It will return filtered query based on those filter condition.
This is constructed using this Stack Overflow answer. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Function Usage Function from sqlalchemy import create_engine from sqlalchemy.</description></item><item><title>How to configure Django and Tornado in PyCharm Community Edition</title><link>https://ruddra.com/how-to-configure-django-tornado-in-pycharm-community-edition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:11:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/how-to-configure-django-tornado-in-pycharm-community-edition/</guid><description>I think, Pycharm is THE best IDE for developing python. But unfortunately, the professional edition is not free. But community edition is good enough for doing debugging, integrating GIT etc.
Normally its easy to use the community edition for django and tornado&amp;rsquo;s debugging/running if you know how to configure. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Django configuration Tornado configuration PyCharm 2016 Django configuration For django&amp;rsquo;s configuration, there is 5 easy steps:</description></item><item><title>Some Useful Tools/Function for Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/some-useful-tools-function/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:56:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/some-useful-tools-function/</guid><description>This post is deprecated as its based on Django 1.6 mostly.
I am going to share some useful Django tools/functions which are very useful(were for me atleast) to get things done. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Return any model class and its properties Distance calculator Dynamic relational operations Get week list Get month list Return any model class and its properties This method will return any model class if you have the name of the class.</description></item><item><title>Working with Formsets</title><link>https://ruddra.com/working-with-formset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 17:49:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/working-with-formset/</guid><description>This post is deprecated and may not be useful.
As django documentation says:
A formset is a layer of abstraction to work with multiple forms on the same page. It can be best compared to a data grid.
So here I am going to show a very simple django formset implementation example.</description></item><item><title>Sample Ajax GET/POST Request in Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/sample-ajax-get-post-request-in-django/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 17:29:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/sample-ajax-get-post-request-in-django/</guid><description>Let us make a test scenario here: A dropdown field which on change we are going to send a Get/Post request to Django and return response.
Let us start coding&amp;hellip;. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; HTML code Create an Ajax request Handle AJAX request in django view In conclusion HTML code &amp;lt;select id=&amp;#34;select_dropdown&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;#34;joshua&amp;#34;&amp;gt;joshua&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;#34;peter&amp;#34;&amp;gt;peter&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; .</description></item><item><title>Using IntellijIdea/Pycharm Within An Exisiting Virtualenv</title><link>https://ruddra.com/using-intellijidea-within-an-exisiting-virtualenv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 17:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/using-intellijidea-within-an-exisiting-virtualenv/</guid><description>To add a virtual environment to Intellij Idea, You have added Python from virtualenv folder to project SDK. Which means that virtualenv directory&amp;rsquo;s python( for example venv/bin/python2.7) needs to be added to Intellij Idea project path. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; For PyCharm &amp;gt;= 2018 For Pycharm 2016 and later For older versions For PyCharm &amp;gt;= 2018 As per documentation from Pycharm:</description></item><item><title>Implementation of Forgot/Reset Password Feature in Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/implementation-of-forgot-reset-password-feature-in-django/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 18:13:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/implementation-of-forgot-reset-password-feature-in-django/</guid><description>Django has its own implementation for reset/forgot password for its admin site. We are going to use that code as reference to implement similar feature for a non admin-site authentication page. Although there are tons of good packages which will allow user to use their password resetting system. But if the system isn&amp;rsquo;t too complex and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need such authentication plugins, then reusing the django&amp;rsquo;s very own implementation can be a good option.</description></item><item><title>Perodic Tasks By Celery 3.1 Example</title><link>https://ruddra.com/perodic-tasks-by-celery-3-1-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/perodic-tasks-by-celery-3-1-example/</guid><description>This post is deprecated. It is no longer compatible with latest Celery versions.
I am assuming you have read celery docs from Celery Documentation.
As we know, celery can be used as a scheduler for executing asynchronous tasks in periodic cycles. Here I am going to share to do that with a code example.</description></item><item><title>Syncdb vs Migration</title><link>https://ruddra.com/syncdb-vs-migration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/syncdb-vs-migration/</guid><description>While surfing through Stack Overflow, I find a common question among Django users that, database not working properly; fields attribute changed, yet not working etc. Clearly because most of them used syncdb after altering fields. Well, lets make some things clear here about django syncdb and migration. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; What is &amp;lsquo;syncdb&amp;rsquo; What is &amp;lsquo;migration&amp;rsquo; What if you mess-up in production server with &amp;lsquo;syncdb&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;migration&amp;rsquo; What is &amp;lsquo;syncdb&amp;rsquo; syncdb is a command which is executed in django shell to create tables for first time for apps which are added to INSTALLED_APPS of settings.</description></item><item><title>RichText Editor in Django Admin Site</title><link>https://ruddra.com/richtext-editor-in-django-admin-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 10:44:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/richtext-editor-in-django-admin-site/</guid><description>I wanted to add a rich text editor within django administrator. It is not that hard to add a rich text editor, as there are editors like CKeditor, Tinymce. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Download ckeditor file Writing forms.py Generated text Download ckeditor file There are multiple plugins for django like django-ckeditor or django-tinymce etc.</description></item><item><title>Django Translation Using .PO File</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-translation-using-po-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 10:51:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-translation-using-po-file/</guid><description>This post is deprecated. Please follow the official documentation.
When comes to using multiple languages in one single site, Django is very handy. You can use .po file to do your translation for you. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; How to do that How to do that Process is very simple: First create .</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://ruddra.com/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/about/</guid><description>Hi, my name is Arnab Kumar Shil, I am a Engineering Doctorate (EngD) Trainee (Software Technology) at Eindhoven University of Technology, Netherlands. My interests are mostly in Programming (in Python, JavaScript and more), DevOps, Tooling, Data Science, Supply Chain, AI, and travelling. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Open Source Contributions Stack Overflow Papers About this website Open Source Contributions Here are some of my open-source projects whice I’ve written in the past or currently maintaining:</description></item><item><title>Contact Me</title><link>https://ruddra.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/contact/</guid><description>I am reachable on all major social media like facebook, twitter, linkedin etc. You can contact me via email as well. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; My email address Before contacting me via email My email address Contact me at me&amp;#64;ignoreme-ruddra&amp;#46;com.
Before contacting me via email I would appreciate if you do not send email for following reasons:</description></item></channel></rss>