<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID-19 on Ruddra</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/covid-19/<description>Recent content in COVID-19 on Ruddra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastbuilddate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:02 +0600</lastbuilddate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Visualization and Result</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones-visualization-results/<pubdate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:02 +0600</pubdate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones-visualization-results/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission. This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we are going visualize the data, discuss about the results and draw a conclusion.</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Methodology</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones-methodology/<pubdate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:01 +0600</pubdate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones-methodology/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission. This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this article we are going to describe the methodology we used in step by step: Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: New York city data with latitude and longitude Step two: New York city data with population Step three: combine step one and step two Step four: collect hospital data from Foursquare Step five: collect hospital bed data from NYS Health Profile Step six: combine step four and step five Step seven: combine data from step three and step six Step eight: add bed and icu per hundred people to data frame Step nine: K-means clustering Step ten: merge cluster labels with dataset Step eleven: see which borough goes to which cluster Step twelve: neighborhoods without hospital Conclusion</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Data Preparation</title><link>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones/<pubdate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubdate><guid>https://ruddra.com/posts/project-battle-of-capstones/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this report has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission. This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we will discuss about business problem and data preparation steps. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Business problem Data Approach Data preparation Source code Conclusion</description></item></channel></rss>