<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub on Coding Blog By Arnab Shil</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub on Coding Blog By Arnab Shil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 18:51:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Run Github Actions Within Monthly Limit</title><link>https://ruddra.com/run-github-actions-within-limits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 18:51:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/run-github-actions-within-limits/</guid><description>Suppose you are using Github free plan, you are running actions in your private repo and keep exceeding the monthly minutes limit, then this article is going to help you to make optimized usage of the actions minutes in step by step manner. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: run workflow on schedule instead of push Step two: run workflow manually only if you push In conclusion Step one: run workflow on schedule instead of push Rather than running the workflow on every push, you can run it in a periodic manner.</description></item><item><title>Serverless and Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/serverless-and-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 22:47:51 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/serverless-and-actions/</guid><description>In JAMStack(aka static sites), we use different paid/free services for things like using Disqus for commenting, MailChimp for newsletters etc. These services come with a tradeoff, for example lack of privacy, bloated JavaScript and many more.
What if we can build them on our own using a serverless stack, with low to no cost and almost zero maintenance?</description></item><item><title>Progressive Web App in Hugo using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 15:53:45 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-implement-pwa/</guid><description>We all know or heard of Progressive Web Apps. I wanted to implement it because it enables web applications workable in offline, like a native app. Also it provides content faster by caching them.
With help of github actions and gulp, we can easily add it to a static site deployed in Github pages.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Deploy Static Site using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:59:54 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/hugo-deploy-static-page-using-github-actions/</guid><description>If you are using Hugo to generate static pages, you are familiar with CLI commands which are to build the static pages in your local machine and make push to your &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io repository. When it comes to using Hugo for blogging, compared to platforms like Medium or WordPress, it is very painful because you do not have any web interface to make changes whenever you want or wherever you want.</description></item></channel></rss>