<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MySQL on Ruddra</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/mysql/</link><description>Recent content in MySQL on Ruddra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:53:28 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ship Application with Database Inside Docker Container</title><link>https://ruddra.com/ship-application-with-database-inside-docker-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:53:28 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/ship-application-with-database-inside-docker-container/</guid><description>DISCLAIMER: This is not the recommended process. Ideally you should have the database running in a separate container and use network to interact with that container.
Usually, we don’t ship application with the database inside the same container. But sometimes we are forced to do that. In this article we are going to see a minimalist way of shipping application with database built-in inside docker container.</description></item><item><title>Install MySQL and MySQLClient(Python) in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/install-mysql-and-mysqlclientpython-in-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 23:59:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/install-mysql-and-mysqlclientpython-in-macos/</guid><description>Connecting to MySQL from Python in MacOS is a very problematic and painful process. In this post, we are going to see how to install MySQL and connect a Python application to it using mysqlclient.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: install Homebrew Step two: install MySQL Step three: install MySQL-Connector-C Step four: install XCode-Select Step five: install OpenSSL Step six: unlink MySQL and link MySQL-Connector-C Step seven: install mysqlclient Step eight: link MySQL back again Step nine: add mysqlclient in virtual env(optional) In conclusion</description></item><item><title>Deploy Django to OpenShift 3 Powered by MySQL and Gunicorn</title><link>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-to-openshift-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 13:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/deploy-django-to-openshift-3/</guid><description>If you want to use OpenShift for deploying Django, you can follow this post and simply do that. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn Kubernetes. We will use docker file only. No other fancy stuff.
Also, before starting, I am also hoping you are little bit familiar with OpenShift 3 and oc tools.</description></item><item><title>Make .CSV file using MySQL and Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</guid><description>In this blog, I am going to show how to develop an application by which we can make .csv files from MySQL database using Python.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps SQL command Run SQL command in python To csv In conclusion
Steps SQL command Now, let us start by getting data from Database.</description></item></channel></rss>