<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travelling on Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/travelling/</link><description>Recent content in Travelling on Coding Blog By Arnab Kumar Shil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:18:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/travelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Travel] Bandarban: In Search of Waterfalls</title><link>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-nafakhum-amiakhum-satbhaikhum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:18:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-nafakhum-amiakhum-satbhaikhum/</guid><description>Bandarban is a heaven for trekking for Bangladeshi people. There are lots of hills around the district, and there are some amazing waterfall as well. I visited three amazing waterfalls named Nafakhum, AmiaKhum, Satbhaikhum. Khum means waterfall in Marma language.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Thanchi Remakri Nafakhum Amiakhum Padma Jhiri Tindu</description></item><item><title>[Travel] Bandarban: Journey to Keokradong</title><link>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-journey-to-keokaradong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 16:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/bandarban-journey-to-keokaradong/</guid><description>Bandarban is a beautiful district of Bangladesh. You will see lots of amazing mountains which are part of Arakan range. Keokradong is the 3rd highest pick**(after Tajingdong and Saka Haphong, references are here) of Bangladesh, which is situated in Bandarbans. So today I am going to share my experience visiting there.</description></item><item><title>[Travel] Journey to the Land of Thunder Dragon</title><link>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-bhutan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 18:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/journey-to-bhutan/</guid><description>I went to Bhutan on September, 2015. It was my best trip ever, really ever. From Dhaka, we went there by DRUK AIR. We(me and two of my friends) landed in Paro Airport. It was really wonderful airport, it was small but clean and organised. After getting out of the plan, a chilling air struck us, and instantly we knew, we gonna like this country.</description></item></channel></rss>