<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Ruddra</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Ruddra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:02 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Visualization and Result</title><link>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-visualization-and-result/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:02 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-visualization-and-result/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we are going visualize the data, discuss about the results and draw a conclusion.</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Methodology</title><link>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-methodology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-methodology/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this article has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this article we are going to describe the methodology we used in step by step: Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: New York city data with latitude and longitude Step two: New York city data with population Step three: combine step one and step two Step four: collect hospital data from Foursquare Step five: collect hospital bed data from NYS Health Profile Step six: combine step four and step five Step seven: combine data from step three and step six Step eight: add bed and icu per hundred people to data frame Step nine: K-means clustering Step ten: merge cluster labels with dataset Step eleven: see which borough goes to which cluster Step twelve: neighborhoods without hospital Conclusion</description></item><item><title>Find Best Neighborhood to Fight Pandemic in NYC - Data Preparation</title><link>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-data-preparation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/find-best-neighborhood-to-fight-pandemic-in-nyc-data-preparation/</guid><description>Disclaimer: this report has been generated as part of IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course&amp;rsquo;s final submission.
This report consists of three parts: business problem and data preparation, methodology, visualization and results. In this part, we will discuss about business problem and data preparation steps. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Business problem Data Approach Data preparation Source code Conclusion</description></item><item><title>Django Access URL Arguments Through Middleware</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-access-url-arguments-through-middleware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 22:06:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-access-url-arguments-through-middleware/</guid><description>Lets say you have an API which is being used by many stores. Now for a specific store ABC, they want to have a different response format. So how would you make this implementation generic without making different views for store ABC? Simple, use middleware.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; How it works Usage Another usage scenario</description></item><item><title>Install MySQL and MySQLClient(Python) in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/install-mysql-and-mysqlclientpython-in-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 23:59:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/install-mysql-and-mysqlclientpython-in-macos/</guid><description>Connecting to MySQL from Python in MacOS is a very problematic and painful process. In this post, we are going to see how to install MySQL and connect a Python application to it using mysqlclient.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: install Homebrew Step two: install MySQL Step three: install MySQL-Connector-C Step four: install XCode-Select Step five: install OpenSSL Step six: unlink MySQL and link MySQL-Connector-C Step seven: install mysqlclient Step eight: link MySQL back again Step nine: add mysqlclient in virtual env(optional) In conclusion</description></item><item><title>Create Proxy Object in Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/create-proxy-object-in-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 01:06:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/create-proxy-object-in-python/</guid><description>Lets say you have been using a class named ClassA, objects created from that class has been used in many places. Now you have a requirement that you need to make a simillar class ClassB, which has almost simillar functionality. Objects of ClassA and ClassB will have simillar method signatures, and could be swapable.</description></item><item><title>Use VS Code for Python and Django Development</title><link>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-for-python-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 16:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/vs-code-for-python-development/</guid><description>Visual Studio Code is an editor developed by Microsoft. I have been using this editor for Python development for sometime now. Previously I have been using PyCharm Community Edition for development, but I had to switch to an editor which was less resource consuming than PyCharm, since I have been using VS Code.</description></item><item><title>Play With Pillow</title><link>https://ruddra.com/play-with-pillow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 14:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/play-with-pillow/</guid><description>Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t heard PIL? It&amp;rsquo;s an image processing library made by python (Python Image Library). Pillow is an extension of it.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Installation Resize image Crop image in box shape Resize image and crop in center to convert it to a fixed size Paste image over a background image Draw text over an image Adjast brightness of an image Adjast color of an image Save the PIL image in django models or serve as django file Convert to webp Convert to JPG/JPEG And Many more</description></item><item><title>Python: Selenium with PhantomJs to capture Screenshots</title><link>https://ruddra.com/python-selenium-with-phantomjs-to-capture-screenshots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/python-selenium-with-phantomjs-to-capture-screenshots/</guid><description>This article is deprecated as PhantomJs has been deprecated from Selenium as driver.
PhantomJS is a headless WebKit script-able with a JavaScript API. It has fast and native support for various web standards: DOM handling, CSS selector, JSON, Canvas, and SVG. And Selenium is a portable software-testing framework for web applications.</description></item><item><title>Make MacOS Notifications From RSS Feed Using Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</guid><description>Today we are going to see how make OSX notifications from RSS Feed of any website using Python.
So first of all, let us see how to make a simple notification. We are going to use AppleScript for this.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Command for notification in AppleScript Start coding for application Integrate AppleScript in application In conclusion</description></item><item><title>Make .CSV file using MySQL and Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-csv-file-using-mysql-and-python/</guid><description>In this blog, I am going to show how to develop an application by which we can make .csv files from MySQL database using Python.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Steps SQL command Run SQL command in python To csv In conclusion
Steps SQL command Now, let us start by getting data from Database.</description></item><item><title>Make a Blog using Django Part 2</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:29:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-2/</guid><description>This post is now deprecated. Please follow the official tutorial for creating your first django application.
From previous post, you have configured and ran django, also added admin site to the django.
To view the working source of this tutorial, check here at: https://github.com/ruddra/myblog/
Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Create entry in database Templates Separating views Create entry in database Now click on the myblog section and click add to add new blog.</description></item><item><title>Make a Blog using Django Part 1</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:29:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-a-blog-using-django-part-1/</guid><description>This post is now deprecated. Please follow the official tutorial for creating your first django application.
&amp;ldquo;Making a blog using django&amp;rdquo; - is probably the most made tutorial of Django. This post is no different. But I made this in my own way using some of django&amp;rsquo;s built-in features so that less coding is required and making it more understandable with minimum packages to use.</description></item><item><title>Dynamically constructing filters based on string input using SQLAlchemy</title><link>https://ruddra.com/dynamically-constructing-filters-based-on-string-input-using-sqlalchemy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/dynamically-constructing-filters-based-on-string-input-using-sqlalchemy/</guid><description>Here I am going to write a dynamic filter. This filter is made for python 3. It will take query or model class and filter condition as input, It will return filtered query based on those filter condition.
This is constructed using this StackOverflow answer.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Function Usage</description></item><item><title>How to configure Django and Tornado in PyCharm Community Edition</title><link>https://ruddra.com/how-to-configure-django-tornado-in-pycharm-community-edition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 21:11:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/how-to-configure-django-tornado-in-pycharm-community-edition/</guid><description>I think, Pycharm is THE best IDE for developing python. But unfortunately, the professional edition is not free. But community edition is good enough for doing debugging, integrating GIT etc.
Normally its easy to use the community edition for django and tornado&amp;rsquo;s debugging/running if you know how to configure.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Django configuration Tornado configuration PyCharm 2016</description></item><item><title>Some Useful Tools/Function for Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/some-useful-tools-function/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:56:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/some-useful-tools-function/</guid><description>This post is deprecated as its based on Django 1.6 mostly.
I am going to share some useful Django tools/functions which are very useful(were for me atleast) to get things done.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Return any model class and its properties Distance calculator Dynamic relational operations Get week list Get month list</description></item><item><title>Implementation of Forgot/Reset Password Feature in Django</title><link>https://ruddra.com/implementation-of-forgot-reset-password-feature-in-django/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 18:13:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/implementation-of-forgot-reset-password-feature-in-django/</guid><description>Django has its own implementation for reset/forgot password for its admin site. We are going to use that code as reference to implement similar feature for a non admin-site authentication page. Although there are tons of good packages which will allow user to use their password resetting system. But if the system isn&amp;rsquo;t too complex and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need such authentication plugins, then reusing the django&amp;rsquo;s very own implementation can be a good option.</description></item><item><title>Django Translation Using .PO File</title><link>https://ruddra.com/django-translation-using-po-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 10:51:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/django-translation-using-po-file/</guid><description>This post is deprecated. Please follow the official documentation.
When comes to using multiple languages in one single site, Django is very handy. You can use .po file to do your translation for you.Table of contents&amp;nbsp; How to do that
How to do that Process is very simple: First create .</description></item></channel></rss>