<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MacOS on Coding Blog By Arnab Shil</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/macos/</link><description>Recent content in MacOS on Coding Blog By Arnab Shil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:25:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix Python After Brew Upgrade in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/fix-python-after-brew-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:25:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/fix-python-after-brew-upgrade/</guid><description>When you run brew upgrade or brew upgrade &amp;lt;package&amp;gt;, all the packages are upgraded or packages linked to that particular package you want to upgrade gets updated. For Python, if the version upgrade is minor, then it should be fine. But major updates break a lot of development setup like, if you are used to develop using virtual environment, then you might have re-install every package.</description></item><item><title>Install MySQL and MySQLClient (Python) in MacOS</title><link>https://ruddra.com/install-mysqlclient-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 23:59:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/install-mysqlclient-macos/</guid><description>Connecting to MySQL from Python in MacOS is a very problematic and painful process. In this post, we are going to see how to install MySQL and connect a Python application to it using mysqlclient. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Step one: install Homebrew Step two: install MySQL Step three: install MySQL-Connector-C Step four: install XCode-Select Step five: install OpenSSL Step six: unlink MySQL and link MySQL-Connector-C Step seven: install mysqlclient Step eight: link MySQL back again Step nine: add mysqlclient in virtual env(optional) In conclusion Step one: install Homebrew You need to install Homebrew in you local machine.</description></item><item><title>Make MacOS Notifications From RSS Feed Using Python</title><link>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/make-apple-notifications-from-rss-feed-using-python/</guid><description>Today we are going to see how make OSX notifications from RSS Feed of any website using Python.
So first of all, let us see how to make a simple notification. We are going to use AppleScript for this. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Command for notification in AppleScript Start coding for application Integrate AppleScript in application In conclusion Command for notification in AppleScript Go to terminal and Type:</description></item></channel></rss>