<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS on Ruddra</title><link>https://ruddra.com/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on Ruddra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 20:19:01 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruddra.com/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Run a Build in AWS CodeBuild When a Git Tag is Pushed</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-git-tags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 20:19:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-git-tags/</guid><description>AWS CodeBuild has nice integration with different Git repository hosting service providers(like GitHub, BitBucket, even amazon&amp;rsquo;s own CodeCommit etc). Even using WebHook is pretty easy. You can start a build in CodeBuild for every push, pull, PR created, PR merged etc. But it can be bit tricky when it comes to trigger for every tag push only, as it us not a default event type provided by CodeBuild.</description></item><item><title>Use Docker for Accessing Database in AWS CodeBuild</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:08:29 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-codebuild-use-database/</guid><description>AWS CodeBuild is an extraordinary tool for building your code. Recently I have been using it to build projects and store docker images in AWS ECR. During those CodeBuild processes, I needed Database for running tests. As the need of the Database was for a limited time and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay extra for it(that is why I did not use AWS RDS), I decided to create database using docker inside CodeBuild.</description></item><item><title>Do Extra in S3 Using Django Storage and Boto3</title><link>https://ruddra.com/aws-boto3-useful-functions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 01:49:10 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ruddra.com/aws-boto3-useful-functions/</guid><description>Today, I am going to write about few useful snippets/functionalities which I have used for Amazon S3 or any S3 compitable storage using Boto3 and Django Storage. FYI, this post focuses on using S3 with Django.
So without further ado, let us begin. Table of contents&amp;nbsp; Configuring S3 Using S3 which it does not belong to AWS Serve S3 in different domain(through cloudFront or varnish) Create new bucket See all buckets Change access control to a bucket Delete objects from a bucket(also bucket itself) Use different folders when storing media and static contents Make &amp;lsquo;collect static&amp;rsquo; faster Check ACL status In conclusion</description></item></channel></rss>